[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
hey hello welcome people of earth i'm
happy you are here
it's me your host a green bean
today we have crystal diamond on the
podcast we talk all things growth
all things changing all things artistry
uh
social media influencers learning from
your mistakes
uh honoring yourself accepting growth
it's great we talk so much great stuff
on here i hope you enjoyed the episode
if you do
make sure you share it make sure you
like make sure you follow make sure you
leave a review if you have some time
i appreciate all of that if you want to
stay posted on what's going on in the
world of junkyard love
in the uh creations of what i'm creating
as my alias jacob from the internet
follow me on instagram jacob from the
internet i usually keep the podcast
updates there um i post clips there i
post trailers for the podcast there so
check that out jake from the internet on
instagram and also check out crystal
nyman
as well on instagram cheers guys
hope you enjoy the episode
smoking like had to get rid of it
nicotine's a hell of a drug though yeah
yeah
yeah she's so addictive like you quite
cool i feel like the first time i quit
smoking cigarettes it was
i went like six months without smoking
and then it was on my birthday and i was
like i'm gonna have a cigarette when i'm
out and then quitting after that it's i
mean you're like you have a pack
so you're like goes from smoking when
you're drinking to like yeah i'll have
one
yeah you're like i'm not gonna throw
away the pack yeah
yeah no it's it's good the vape i don't
know how to feel about it but it's
better than a cigarette so
that's kind of how i feel when i buy um
like all my cookies or something and i'm
like i'll spread this out for a few days
and then like
yeah anyway i'm like i'm i'm killing
this box for sure i know
that's we had um some friends over for
super bowl
and we have so many like chips and
snacks and things and it's like
you have them you're like oh i'll just
like dabble and then you're like no that
bag is gone
i'm going ham yeah yesterday was like
where's that nacho cheese i was like i
put some in a bowl and then i was like
get rid of it get rid of it he's like
boy you threw it out it was perfectly
like you waste so much food i'm like
[__] no i know well dude i do the same
thing though because i'll
i'll enjoy it at first or i'll you know
over-indulge from shopping or whatever
and then
like i said i think i'm spreading it out
and then i'm sitting there eating the
whole [__] bag and i just can't stop
so a lot of times i'll literally just
throw away the last halfway
it seems wasteful but i don't know what
are you gonna do with the bag
yeah um hey when was the first time
that you do you remember the first time
you smoked a cigarette
yeah i was actually in high school yeah
it was about at a party or
yeah i had um people up at my house
actually
and it was a camel turkish gold
you remember the type yeah and then you
know what was actually i remember going
up and visiting
uh my friend mary in seattle and she had
the
it was like a camel pack but it was
black pink
and teal so appealing where you're like
oh i want to smoke that it was like a
light menthol
i thought it was so cool too is that
funny how the companies play to like
you know young people like pretty colors
that was a cigarette for like
young girls for sure the young girl
cigarette now now everybody smokes the
jewels i feel like the
i hope that we don't learn that you know
they're worse for us in the long run but
it seems i don't know it seems better
it's like
there's not like that heat going
directly to you well i think too
like of course we're always going to
find new things um and you're always
justifying
your vices right right i think
so i smoked the jewel for a long time
and that was good because like i stopped
smoking the cigarettes it's crazy
because i actually
um my boyfriend will his younger brother
he's in high school and like that's the
one who i saw it from like every he's
like
half the people in high school smoke it
and so
he's the one that got me started on that
so i smoked the jewel and then there was
all that stuff like do you remember when
it was like vape
you know people are in the hospital for
vapes and all this stuff yeah yeah
looking back i'm like was that the
beginning of covid um
oh [__] i didn't even think about that
right so there's that scared that and so
i was like all right i have to stop the
jewel
and so i would stop the jewel but then
the next thing you know i'm like
i have my american spirits back and like
doing hair you can't smoke
and do hair it's just like you can't be
smelling like a cigarette and like up
close with someone so
it's like that balance of all right do i
really want to smoke but you you mean
you get off work and you're like that's
what you look forward to it's a
cigarette
um but i feel like i've like dabbled
back and forth but they made those like
puff bars now
and so i like looking
i'm like the puff bars are terrible
because that's like it's in a
plastic first of all like the waist like
you're wasting so much just plastic
because you use it once and then you
throw it out
but the jewels like at least you're
gonna lose are using the smaller
things but again so i was trying to quit
the jewel so then you're like okay well
i'll just buy a puff bar kind of like
the indulging with the chips where it's
like
this is gonna limit me you know this
will be it um
but those i would feel like when i'm
working out like you would feel them
in your chest so i think with stuff like
that where it's not
regulated i would like compare it back
like okay well at least joule
is like a regulated thing um
and then i more recently have switched
to the sworn
which you buy like the salt nicotine and
you can get like a lower dose so i think
as far as like trying to quit something
that's probably the best way because you
can actually monitor the amount of
nicotine that you're getting
and you know what's going on yeah and it
lasts so much longer
there's not as much waste like your
device lasts
longer and then it has like a coil that
you switch out so
so i had a i had a pax pen
which was it was thc in mine uh this is
a while back ago but it was
i remember the coolest part about it was
um it was connected to an iphone app
it's connected to bluetooth
and so you can set like your temperature
settings you know based off of like
what your it was a session i think they
would call it yeah
and basically it was good because i
would notice you know just like just
like we would all do you know when it
comes to cigarettes or
or vapes or you know you know the thc
pens whatever
it's almost kind of like if you're
getting stressed out or you're nervous
you're like say you're at a social
setting
you step outside you're going to be like
you know
your breath of fresh air so to say and
uh i really like the
the pack spin because the app
i would notice that i would like stress
smoke it like i would be getting anxiety
i'm like oh i'm just gonna try to get
really high to what i don't know
whatever was in my head
and so on the app you could set it to be
like 60 seconds and then the thing locks
oh wow you can't just sit there if
you're stressed out just outside for
five minutes like if you set your little
session time so
that was kind of cool you know i we
gotta we have all these really cool
you know updated technology and these
cool cool new ways to get
you know a little bit altered states of
consciousness or reduce stress or reduce
like all these things you know the
the craziness of the world it's it's
kind of cool that
technology changes changes along with it
we could slowly like wean off or kind of
control our vices to some extent i guess
again
that might be justification but no i get
that
um i mean that's like the double double
edged sword see where you're like
so much technology is so nice but then
like i was watching um
judas and the black messiah the other
night um which very good movie highly
recommend
um but we were just talking about like
times were just so different and with
that actually netflix has a movie
chicago seven so we watched the two of
those and we're like
back then it's just so crazy because you
don't have like the instant technology
and the social media and stuff where
messages are you know shared so quickly
um but talking about that too i feel
like
we're just so much more fast paced now
because we do have technology and all
this stuff like it's like you constantly
want
like it's feeding the you know and i
feel
with that like you have anxiety and
stuff like that um
yeah so it's interesting i'm like
sometimes i wish i grew up in the 70s
and then you see what was really going
on and then you're like
okay like at least we're like you know
able to
become more aware and talk about these
things that have kind of been just
pushed
along you know and we're talking like
they uh
cover the vietnam war and how like we
weren't supposed to be there
you know and it's just interesting
you know how things have changed but
technology i feel like is giving a
forefront to people to be able to kind
of spread their messages and stuff like
that so
right yeah it definitely has i mean i
i think i think our generation like
really thinking about
how much i always try to rephrase this
and i always try to find like the
correct phrasing because i don't want to
sound like oh we know more than our
parents by far
because it's not necessarily that i mean
i get but like if you do want to
quantify sheer information like how much
information is shoved into our brains
like me
already this morning i was up at i don't
know 7 45 and right away i'm like
listening to
like youtube lectures and i like listen
to multiple things i listen to
that the ass end of a podcast as i was
just showering
like we're always inserting new
information new perspectives and those
new perspectives who are people
talking now like um like they're also
kind of younger people who
who grew up in in this era they're also
doing the same thing so the flow
of information the flow of like new
thoughts
new ways of being knowing information
like it's it's almost um it's beautiful
but it can be crippling in a sense too
i think like knowing everything i mean
there's almost something i think about
the
like when you're walking down down the
street and you know there's a homeless
person and you kind of like
because you can't just like you know
withdraw all the money
from your bank account every time you
see a homeless person and give them
their money to get you know
back up on their luck but there's almost
other layers of stuff like that where we
walk past a homeless person we kind of
have to deny our inner humanity
we also almost have to deny like
like when i'm eating a tomato i have to
kind of not think about the fact that it
could have been
like child slavery way across the world
you know there's just so much
information that comes with everything
that we're doing that we almost have to
like
choose to block some of it out in a way
yeah
it's interesting that you brought up the
homeless thing too because um
obviously i work in center city so in
philadelphia you see a lot of that
um but i have thought the other day
honestly like two days ago
i was leaving and there was a guy
outside he's like hey can you help me
out and like
you know he really looked like he needed
some help and i when i first moved to
college i got
played by so many people like i saw a
woman she gave me this story and i'm
like
like didn't have hardly any money gave
her like five dollars i see her the next
day
and she has a different story i mean it
was like cancer the first time and then
it was her boyfriend's beating her and
i'm like oh
but i had the other day i had just the
thought because he had asked me and i
really don't have any
like cash on me and you know we always
talk about cash is king and i think with
technology and things moving i'm like so
at what point are we going to be
like everything's digital and like when
you want to give someone like
some money you just like to bump your
phones together and like transfer your
money
you know like things like that where i'm
like i
feel like as much as it's like you don't
think that it could go there
and that's a possibility of like you
know everything becomes so
digital yes yeah i mean where we
are our generation broad broad blanket
stroke there our generation is like
like we're really having to figure out
very quickly
how to deal with all this technological
change and like it's changing
us like literally who humans are you the
who the human species is and what we're
capable of and what we're capable of
knowing and
and how i mean the fact that i've said
this before the fact that
right now on this podcast i could if i
knew someone you know in china
i could just chime them in and they can
turn their phone around and i see
exactly what's going on in china right
now
like that's pretty crazy compared to
like we're do we're just the thing that
came after apes
like what the hell we're able to see a
portal across the world now
i know i think with that too there is
like a bit of anxiety
like for instance with me with um
my career path like a huge thing of it
is
having to have some sort of social media
presence because
you know you got to get yourself out
there and like i have so much anxiety
about
you know originally deciding to do the
podcast because i just feel like
i'm i mean not super uncomfortable
because i'm talking to you but like if i
were to just have to like talk to my
camera like
and give tutorials and things like that
i'm super uncomfortable talking to
no one you know so it's been a huge
thing i was listening to a podcast the
other day
um it helps like stylists with the whole
business side of things and they were
covering social media and like where you
need to be putting the most of your time
and things like that and
you know i have this extra layer of
anxiety that
is kind of you know debilitating in the
sense of like
okay you got to tear down that wall and
stop being fearful of this because that
is you know a next step for you to be
able to you know share
what you know and you know there's so
much knowledge about little things i was
blowing out my hair today i'm like
you know people don't know you can do
this trick or that trick and you know
there is knowledge to be shared
is just kind of getting rid of that fear
of
you know putting yourself out there also
like being the center of attention i
have a hard time with that like i do so
many um
weddings and things like that and the
more i do i'm like i don't want that day
where it's like
all about you tension's on you you know
like that's i mean like
you know we can have like a party and
stuff but i don't want it to be like
centered around i don't have a hard time
with that side of things
no i totally get that in what you said
about like kind of running your business
your brand
your like artistry on social media
that's super rough i struggled with that
a lot too did like
um yesterday for example i was listening
to garyvee i always try to like sprinkle
in some garyvee
just because i get a little too ethereal
and sometimes i'm like oh yeah like i've
got a you know i have to make money and
i have you know business and like things
like that so i have to try to sharpen
that so i'll listen to gary vee but
yesterday he was talking about um
linkedin
essentially like and i was just sitting
there thinking like that like low level
level of anxiety just immediately like
crap i'm not doing enough on linkedin
crap i'm like gonna miss this whole wave
great i i'm missing out all these people
are surpassing me
in in this area of business and whatever
it's it's really hard though because
i feel like you might be able to relate
with with this i feel like pretty
fully because
when you consider yourself just like
like an artist of sorts like i'm a
creator or
like yeah yeah i do djing but i'm also
doing podcasts and i'm also like trying
to put my thoughts out or i'm trying to
whatever
and like you're also designing people's
looks you're like
you're you're drawing who they could
potentially be you know it's like it's
so it's so much artistry in itself so
sometimes i feel like the artistry or
like the authenticity of
what you're truly doing starts to get
like just a little muddied and murky'd
when you're trying to throw in business
and trying to make sure like
you know like like artistry doesn't
always have that much to do with gdp
you know i think it's hard to like
being an artist is just a tough thing
and it's like it's interesting because
i don't know i feel like it's the same
with like so many different aspects of
art too but it's like as soon as you
like you're an artist but then like at
what point do you become a sellout where
people want to label you like oh
you know and that's a tough thing it's
like okay well if i'm now like making
money or
you know doing these things it's like
ugh their sell out it's like well
that's actually a step and becoming
successful and you know and
it's tough and i see a lot of um
conversation on social media and now too
um there's this uh stylist who's like
calling out like
she's like i'm get invited to these like
um
educational forums and she's like i get
so discouraged because as soon as
someone says something that like
other people don't agree with or they're
doing something and they're like oh you
ripped that off of them or like she's
like you know you can't ever get ahead
because there's always people
tearing you down she's like so that's
like a huge
part honestly just stop inviting me
because you know this is supposed to be
an educational platform and all you guys
are doing is just ripping each other
apart
so it's tough like i don't know i think
it
and it's the same thing with like
tattooing and
i think the other hard part about social
media too is like
at what point are you like gonna put
more into your social media than you are
into your craft because like you can get
really good at social media
and like get the right angles or take
the right lighting or
you know do all these things but in
person you're like oh my god i saw their
work and that was like
not what i expected so it's tough with
that side too of like
trying to be authentic and show
a real you know image of what you
are actually capable of so it's tough
with that
yeah it seriously is i think a lot of
artists i feel like a lot of artists can
resonate with that i mean
because so i look back on my instagram i
look back
like when i was pretty much primarily
just djing
but the way that i would
it's interesting how much time i would
put into my social media
like compared to like what the benefits
of me getting like all these cool like
streetwear photos and like
it is cool and it's fun in itself and it
is like yeah you're you're supporting
your brand and you're like
you know you're kind of like taking over
the role of like i guess i am some
some form of influencer or or whatever
we call those
content creators now on social media and
i it's like me going home and setting up
you know taking an
hour to like get the right angles and
like get the right lighting and like oh
what do i want to wear like if i want to
change my shoes or something you know
it's fun but like what if i spend that
hour like practicing my craft of djing
yeah you know what i mean like so it's
kind of hard selling yourself
yeah i think too like a big thing is
there's times where i like look back on
things i've done or like
you know when you have the opportunity
and you're like okay i want to do this
for social media
so often in those moments it's like i'm
actually like the least
satisfied or happy in that moment versus
i'm like damn like
i wish someone was just here like taking
this video right now because like i just
i love that application i love the way
that i painted this or i love the way
that
this turned out and like so often those
like great moments that i have
i'm like i don't have anything to show
for it and the moments where
you know i do get some image i'm like
all right that was like good but it
wasn't my best
you know so it's tough with that too
like trying to
balance showing your art as well as
doing your art so yeah it's it's it's
very interesting i mean uh
capitalism mixed in with like the
essence the soul of a person trying to
create
like from like i'm a human trying to
make something that hasn't been done
before or i'm trying to push the edge of
what
i have done before even like it's it's
hard to match up like oh wait what does
it have to do with
late stage capitalism it's
i think like a big thing that i have a
struggle with is like
i want to like i got into hair it kind
of
whirlwind of a bunch of different
experiences and then like getting into
this i'm like oh
like i knew i was supposed to do this um
but i also feel like
it's tough because
i don't know like you're in the moment
like part of me doing this is like i
want to make people feel good you know
i'm always there
to make someone like the best thing for
me
like gratification is not like oh yeah
like that looked great to me it's like
how that person feels and that person's
like
oh my god like this is amazing i feel so
good like i wish i could go out right
now
like that's that's what i do it for
so it's kind of hard too where you're
like i have to appeal
on a you know behind a screen to show
you know that this is what you can have
but it's hard to like show that
you know so you have to appeal in a way
where you want people to come to you but
i feel like
i don't know it's kind of hard when
you're like chasing likes and things
like that it's like that's not what it's
for it's like i want to make people feel
good so it's
hard when it's coming from you that you
want other people to
feel that you know satisfaction or that
you know getting those likes and things
yeah
it's like when you when you chase the
wrong thing like
i mean you kind of have to chase that
thing which you're posting on social
media but you almost
kind of attract the wrong parts of what
you were trying to get because
because i mean there's no like as i'm
just mindlessly say i wake up in the
morning i'm mindlessly scrolling in my
bed through instagram
and i see your posts it's gonna it's not
going to make me
when i see that i'm not going to say oh
wow that person
experienced incredible happiness joy
like the confidence they had that day
wow you obviously you don't feel that
like it's not we haven't made that
possible through our screens yet anyway
so what what you see is almost what
you're trying to sell
and it's it's interesting because it's
suddenly
in this marketplace i mean i get social
media is kind of inherently a
marketplace anyway especially nowadays
but it's you're suddenly competing
against people that you weren't trying
to compete against
right now you're all of a sudden like oh
well where do you rank against all the
other
hair people in the world you know and
you're like i'm not trying to i'm just
trying to create what i specifically
create from this
this little corner of my life and my
world and
i want to make people happy but when
people see it it's kind of
oh we're comparing you know i actually
see this um
rappers is something i see this a lot
with which you know rappers get a lot of
flack but like
these [__] work hard on the
gram like they they go in
and in a lot of times i i feel like
i'll respect the heck out of them um
like be and there will be people who are
really good like i'm scrolling and get
like a two minute freestyle that's just
fire
but yeah they're comparing it they're
like well he ain't eminem
right he wasn't trying to compare to
eminem like what about how good
he is at what he does and like what he
brings to people with what he has we
social media accidentally makes us
compare everything to everything else
yeah and i think too that's a huge thing
i talk about it all the time i'm like
it's crazy to me that but there's so
many creative people out there
you know like and you can take it to any
industry i'd love to take it to music
because
um you know before kobe my one of my
favorite things about philly is like
whatever kind of music you're into you
can find that music here like live music
you can go to
like a small little bar and get someone
though who's local
who's just playing you're like oh my god
like her voice is absolutely incredible
and it's just like it's hard because
you're like how do
it's hard to make that step to where
you're famous it's like how can we
as a collective world population like we
know certain names like
and that makes sense you know they get
out but how is there not so many more
names
that you know you get to hear all music
like how is it every day i'm not hearing
a new song like hearing something and
it's just it's hard to get to that next
level where it's like
okay like you made it you're on that
next platform like
so i think that's one thing that will be
moving forward is
and we see it now like with social media
um
like influencers but there's like i
think at some point and i think j cole's
actually said this that
you know that at some point there's not
going to be famous people because
you know there's so many people can
branch out and you can get this
widespread
you know where people know you or follow
you and see your stuff
so at what point do we stop like
idolizing certain people and there's a
wider platform
you know there's enough to go around for
everyone so
hopefully at some point we can get to a
place where
you can't share but i guess it starts
with us like i'm saying like i
don't like on social media really push
those limits and do those things
because i feel like to do the things to
get attraction was against what i
actually believe in
myself is like what you should do you
know to have a happy and positive life
like
you don't need this fame or you know i'm
never chasing i don't need to be liked
by everyone
i just want to make good solid collect
connections with the people that
i do meet you know a hundred percent
said beautifully i like that a lot
yeah i think uh i i kind of wonder if
okay i saw this reddit comment a while
it was been a while back now but um
somebody was basically asking i think it
was before covid so they were basically
asking what's different
from when i was in high school that i or
what's something
they were basically asking younger kids
who are in high school right now
what's something that you experience now
that i probably wouldn't believe or that
was different from
my day back in my day or whatever and
the top comment was
we don't really have clicks anymore
everybody just hangs out with who they
want to hang out with
and like within their social community
or
mobile community like so everyone's kind
of connected through
social media in like our avatars on
there and they said there's not
really much of clicks as much anymore
yeah and so i kind of wonder if maybe
where
fame is going it's not like there's not
going to be so many household names
where everybody in your house knows
these certain people
you know like there's you know we're
going to know ellen degeneres we're
going to know the weekend like there is
going to be
you know people who there is generalized
everybody knows about but
under one roof it might be like well
what mom is into
is this stuff and we don't know any of
the people but in her world in her
social you know mobile community like
that's a famous person to her and then
me because i study you know motocross
i know the popular motocross guys so
maybe
we'll just kind of fall more into our
niches of who's popular for what we
truly
enjoy rather than just here's this
person
here's here's cardi b and everybody
needs to love her you know right
right i think to live with that
generation of
i mean i think we have like myspace that
was like the big thing that came out
like when i was in high school and then
towards the very end facebook came up
and i remember my cousin was like he's
in college and he's like wait you have a
facebook he's like you don't have a
college email how do you have that um
but like myspace was our social
you know outlet at that point and i
think now like
i do young girls you know who are in
high school and they come in and like
you know their friends are like oh no
like she goes to a different high school
it's not about who you go to school with
or things like that it's like you have
these different connections and
you know they're always always connected
and they have all these different
you know different groups and things
that they do so that is
actually i talk about that all the time
though with that i feel like
being connected to your phone all the
time um and having
like social media be there when you're
young and you're
learning who you are like feeling the
pressure to post and you know
be yourself but then you know getting
like bullying and things like that like
it's one thing to go to school and deal
with that when you're trying to figure
out like who am i
what do i like um but then to take that
home with you and then have
the you know constant like
it's like a popularity contest all the
time that you're constantly
in i feel like it's just gotta be so
tough
yeah because we get kind of sucked into
the avatars that we're trying to portray
on here on social media and you know uh
like we were just talking about myspace
i mean i i would i loved myspace like
when it first came around
i i wonder i just wonder i wonder how
much it truly changed me
as in like if i had never gotten my
space at those you know crucial ages of
14 15 16 whatever i wonder
like who i would be now i wonder if i
would care that much about social media
now if i care about branding
i wonder if i would care about um i
don't know a lot of the things that i'm
that i'm into now it's almost kind of
like our first little toe dip in the
water i would actually
i would and again this isn't a bad thing
i enjoyed it this was seriously like fun
my friend me and my friends would go
like take photos like oh let's go down
to the railroad tracks
and take you know with our skeleton
fingerless gloves and our eyeliner
and take photos and then like but we
would go start to do things
outside that we could then take from
outside and put online and now it's like
making our social social avatar and
i think the answer that though like i
think the answer is yes like you would
you would be the same it wouldn't you
know change anything because
i think that's why social media is so
big because we realize like we as people
we do
like you know that gratification from
other people we do
like that you know feeding our ego
if you will um but it is interesting to
talk about like going out and taking
your pictures i remember you know you go
from msn days when you're waiting for
the
computer to dial up and you get to sit
and chat
um you're tying up the phone line your
mom's like get off
you know i can't get any phone calls but
that and i remember when my space first
came out digital cameras so my mom got
me this digital camera but you couldn't
see there's no like display
you know so you're just taking random
pictures and we would go outside and we
would take
it would hold 16 pictures so we take 16
pictures
plug it into the usb load down up to or
upload them to the computer and then
you're like oh i don't like to see you
go back out and take more and then i
just had my friend in from
college but uh softball with me did her
hair yesterday
and we're like oh my god we used to go
out
and that's when actual digital cameras
were the thing and we would just go to a
party for a night and we would take a
whole
album full of pictures and upload them
to our
social media and her facebook at that
time and i look back at the pictures now
i'm like it's just
crazy how much it has evolved
in such a short time honestly you know
10 years ago
and yeah yeah like you probably wouldn't
post a majority of those photos now but
back then it was like you make an
album for the night and that was how we
did social media i had to like hide all
of them i'm like oh my god there's so
many pictures just like you know out
college partying
and yeah it's like when you get to your
older
older age you're like okay like i'm a
professional now i can't be having these
college voters be dug up and you know
that's the thing too
it's like so much with sharing there's
so often especially with like
everything that we've gone through um
we've seen so many like huge events take
place
you know uh with racial injustice stuff
and then like
capital rights and all this stuff and
you look at like cameras are everywhere
like
videos are always being taken you know
there's there's so much that like if you
are
doing things that show your true
character and you have
you know these bad things that
you know live within you but they will
be exposed and that's
something to you know it's good and it's
it's
just like it's a wake up for a lot of
people where you don't get to
you know carry on and do these things
without any repercussions because
someone's always watching right yeah
that i mean that's that's the absolute
truth it's it's kind of weird we almost
i always i i don't like i don't think
that we should self-edit ourselves
so much um there's a balance there i
mean there's
i i think the camera or like noticing or
realizing that a camera could could be
watching you or could be like filming
you is enough to wake up a lot of people
and be like oh [__] like i never really
thought about what i said i just
said it i never really thought about my
actions like like of course those people
said that it hurt their feelings when
i said this but they're just sissies and
now you got to be able to like i wonder
how that feels to a lot of these people
when you know they they they act crazy
or they you know maybe not crazy
they they act out of anger or they they
don't have a lot of emotional control
um they're yelling at people i wonder
how it feels to them
to watch that video back of themselves
veins splitting out
red face they're screaming at another
human being
um i i wonder i don't know it's
again we're at this influx this like
mixing pot of technology just like
clashing all these things and basically
saying hey humans like here's all the
things that you weren't noticing you
were doing
wake the hell up and we're we're in a
mixing pot of it
right i think it's really good like as
as much as there's
you know pressure and ways when we're
using it for
you know trying to it's good you can
share
knowledge but i think it's also like i
think
this year has been super tough but i'm
thankful
that this year took place because you
know certain little things like you
reflect and get to see okay like what
are people really experiencing what are
people going through like
where have i maybe turned my back
or you know brushed it off like is not
that important or not even realizing you
know what someone's actually going
through or experiencing
so it's helped me to just have a better
understanding i think
with that you know i always find myself
to be very empathetic
for people and it's kind of pushing
those barriers to go a little bit
further and
um you know i think the only way to make
a better tomorrow is to
you know talk about the things that are
issues
you know there has been a really good
i guess push in like what i see people
sharing like for instance um
i love the jewelry that i make this is
one of my clients
um she's awesome and she has a really
big social media platform
and i've noticed since all the racial
injustice stuff
and you know human rights equal rights
all this
she's really used her platform to um
you know share these things that a lot
of people don't take the time to think
about and like it's just really
enlightening like
i find myself doing little side research
or you know just reaching out to
understand different communities that
i've never
taken the time to look at what they're
going through or how they have been
oppressed and
um you know trying to do things like
even as simple as like having a little
conversation around it with someone who
may have a different view it's like you
wake that next person up so it does help
to kind of unfold and maybe hopefully
you know push towards a better tomorrow
yeah yeah i i think so too i think it
it's uh
you know as much as the platform could
be used for for negative things and
there is negative aspects but there is a
lot of positivity there too again it's
you we now get to point out to people
you have you have popular
like hey we listen to your opinion we
like what you have to say you know
especially when it comes to i imagine as
young people they're probably looking up
at influencers
like just waiting like you tell me how
to be i'm gonna be it and i'm gonna try
that on i'm gonna
i'm gonna see if that works for me and
see if that's a part of me you know
so if we can if if you know influential
people
and people with with big followings can
really you know say hey this is
important and this is something if you
haven't ever thought about it it's worth
a few minutes you know
there's so much it's again like we're
talking about the beginning there's so
much information it's hard to know like
where i got this tomato from and i don't
want to feel guilty about
the child slavery that when they picked
it but there
there is like a small a good healthy
amount of trickle
of self-assessment of who you are and
the things that you say i mean i
like we grew up in the same town and and
i'm still here you know
i notice a lot of the things just by
living in a small town a lot of the
things that i
that i didn't stretch my mind on until i
i went somewhere else or i visited
somewhere
else or i said the wrong thing in the
wrong situation i was like oh [__]
i never like really thought about why i
said that i never really thought about
like why i would
why i would uh interpret things that way
so it's important um it's uh it's also
very triggering to a lot of people
though
like it's like people complain about
other other you know influencers or
whatever
trying to change like dude just just
[__] post hair man
like what you know it's like what what
are you talking about like don't
we we have to treat the social media
thing in the human interaction
the human connection as it actually is
not how we wish that it was
you know and that there's so many
industries i actually just that made me
think of one of the
trainers that i've worked with he's
super super open about you know
political beliefs and things like that
he's not saying like hey this is how it
has to be but he's like
you know if he's experiencing something
he sheds light and people
will always be like man just stick to
kettlebells like you know
shut up like stop and he's like you know
what honestly like you don't have to be
here i'm choosing to share this like i
i'm not making you say like you know get
lost so
that's the thing you're always gonna
have like fall back with
you know haters right always you know
always having something to say
it's always the most negative people who
want to say the most
yeah i mean that's that's what i think
social media i almost think social media
will be better if we just delete
comments and likes how about that
rid of it get rid of follow count
comments and likes and then
give it a couple of years i'm sure a lot
of interest would be lost like people
would be like
there's no way to get popular i don't
really want to do it but it would be
interesting to see what kind of rises to
the surface
you know what just based off of you know
views or
just interest in it and not you know
maybe people like it but that's for the
algorithm to know
i don't get to see the likes i like the
idea of that
that would like i know it's like take
some pressure off
you know and i've never been the type
like people like oh like i'm gonna
delete this and repost it because it
didn't get that many likes i'm like
what does it matter you know like it's
for me
i like social media because that's my
portfolio like if you want to see my
work
you can go to my page and you can view
my work you know so that
that to me i'm like that's it's not
something that you have to print out
have this catalog
of here's what i'm capable of like you
can see what i'm capable of so that's
what's kind of pushed me to be more
active with that is all right show
people you know
what you can do so that way if they're
you know considering
getting their hair done they have a
something to
you know consider your work as an option
for them
and be like if you ever move or go
anywhere else like you have this
piece of your work you know so yeah
exactly yeah it's a portable portfolio
uh
mike posner recently i mean he's not the
only one to do it but
he came out with like this like uh like
mixed ap or ep
before a single or something um i might
have sent it to you guys
it was like it was pretty cool but
anyway essentially what he did
was it was kind of this artist's move
that at the beginning i was like i don't
know how i feel about that and then
afterwards i'm like this is savage as
[__] he deleted
everything from his social medias and
unfollowed everybody
and it was i i was really contemplating
it because
i i've commented on this before i i
never liked when people did that i was
like why would you do that that's a
weird thing to do
but i think it was because i would be i
was like insecure about ever doing that
on my own
into my own profile but now that i don't
know i've changed my perspective on it
now i think that's the most like
g artist thing you could do is just
delete everything delete it all
yeah i actually with his album i liked
at the beginning the first time i went
to listen to it
um he had that little like segment he's
like all right if you don't have time to
dedicate this where you can give your
undivided attention like
don't listen and so i was like you know
what like i actually really appreciate
that i
i love music i always have if that's
been a huge part of
our existence um but
i was like okay like i will actually set
aside the time and
uh new year's eve actually we're going
up to
um the poconos which is like the
mountain towns of the east coast here
um and lana was here visiting so we were
in the car i'm like do you guys care if
i put this on like i've been wanting to
listen to it so we listened to it
on the way up to that and you know like
overall
you know the album it was different than
i expected but i just
i really liked the
the raw like exposure of it
you know it was it's such art like it
was really just a story like i was
i i was involved the whole time i was
like oh like what's going to happen next
but then you're also you know and then
it comes to a song so you're
you're going to enjoy the song and
there's a beat and whatnot and but but
he's really trying to communicate a
story
that in the end communicates like a very
real raw human emotion
and that dude that's such [__] art
like that's just
savage that's what you know in this
world of
there's probably younger people likely
probably listen to more singles than
they do albums
just based off of our attention span and
stuff but there really is something
and even me i listen to a lot of a lot
of singles too you know but there is
something beautiful about an album
and especially you know a little you
know spoken word
sort of artistic poet poetic album like
that
it's really cool i'm just going to
listen to a new album i
will always like make sure that my
shuffle is off and i'll start it
the first song and then go through
because i feel like a lot of times like
you'll miss little things that are
hidden with inside
you know that's like either a story or
you know a certain transition from one
song to another where it's like a second
of those
like that flowed because of this like so
i think it's important to like the first
time i listen to an album to
do it in order yes 100
i totally agree i mean you're not going
to take a book and like shuffle the
pages and see
what story comes out you got to you got
to listen to an album
as if you'd read it just the same way
you'd read a book i like that
hey um when did you how long has it been
now since you had moved to philly
so like how many years is it now so
if you count the years that i was at
temple i'm like
just over a decade um so i was here
2009 and did two years at temple
and then moved home for
because i was there for almost two years
but i came back in 2013
so i've been here since march of 2013 so
come up on eight years
consecutively living out here how do you
think
here's a big question how different do
you think you would be
now if you had never moved so so much
different
it's actually i've like you know just
turned 30 and you get to this point
where you're like
reevaluating life and you're like okay
what's next where do i go
um you know what's in my future and i
just more recently i've had a lot of
like really deep i feel like that's
copa's been good because it's brought a
lot of things to the surface i
i don't think if we were just on this
like rat race of constantly moving that
i would ever
you know take the time to dissect and
like reflect and look at
my feelings you know for a while there i
was like you know what like
i'm out here and i'm i'm gonna
eventually move out west and
i think what that was like some pressure
of okay i'm away from my family
um you know and i came out here to kind
of get away from
from things at that time but then i
realized like
you know my support system's out here i
have such a good group of people like in
my
toughest times i came out here for their
support
so you know with me um in the hair
industry like i
have taken the time i changed salons and
have been able to reflect career-wise
i'm like okay i do want a salon of my
own at some point
and you know why would i put pressure on
myself to
move home and open something up closer
to family when i'd be starting over when
i have so much support out here
um like my friends you know i spent so
many holidays out here with their family
like
i have such a strong group of people
and that was one thing that like when
lana came out here
and our good friend michael came with
they were like you know it's so
beautiful to like come and be a part of
like your friend group like you guys
really have such an amazing thing
and michael may actually said something
too because he had met um
will's friends as well he's like you
know he's like
we we're always with people and like
meeting friends
back home um and in seattle like he's
got his group he's like but i kept
waiting to like
meet the [__] he's like all right yep
this one's gonna be the [__] this
one's gonna be the [__] and he's like
i never met the [__] if you guys
don't have that he's like you really
have such a beautiful
like support system that you have out
here and everyone's unique and everyone
does their own thing and everyone's
supportive of one another
and so i just more recently like
accepted like okay me moving away from
home isn't me
like running out on my my life before
you know it's not like
that's never me that never was me it's
accepting like okay that was me
and now i'm growing and changing and i'm
moving in a different direction and it's
okay to grow it's okay to change it's
okay to
you know be away from your family and
not take the guilt of
oh you ran away from them like no like
they're still my family that's still my
past that's still
part of me but the best thing to do for
myself is to
do a lot of candles actually we um
did acid on new year's eve up in the
mountains it's all snowing and
um i probably do it like once twice a
year and i
i think that ass is such a beautiful
thing because
i always learn it's like you unlock like
uh
you break a coat or you get that extra
little piece of the puzzle you're like
oh like
you've learned things about life and the
one thing that kept coming to me that
night was
to honor yourself and i think that was
like
you know so often we're like worried
about other people and like
i don't know you get like stressed out
like and especially when you're like on
drugs it's like oh is she feeling okay
do they feel okay are they and it's like
the most important thing for you to do
is actually
take care of you because if you're
taking care of you well then you take
out
because i'm like if i'm thinking this
way about them they're thinking the same
way about me
so we'll never maybe meet that
connection or that idea that
understanding of like
yeah i'm good if you're good are you
good it's like if i just do my part
that's all i really can do that's all
that's in my control that really is
benefiting everyone around me so that
was like a big takeaway from my
acid new year's trip and that really has
helped me to
make the decision like okay i am okay
being out here
it is it's what's best for me and it's
like i said it's not
taking away from anything that i was or
you know any i guess
there's no regret to feel and also like
yeah it has changed me a lot but it's
changed me for better
right yeah that's so cool i like i like
that perspective because
you know what like if you're so
concerned i'm like what is this person
thinking about me or like what should i
be doing differently
when you really focus internally on like
okay how like we're almost like
inadvertently taught to reject that in a
weird way
right like we we
it's it's almost like like you like i
don't know self-care even
like analyzing like oh like how do i
honor myself what is that like who who
ever asks themself that
how do i honor myself like how like and
how much better
is your day if you wake up and you put
both feet on the floor and you're like
how could i honor myself today like how
could i
best honor like my internal being in the
best of like what i want
and then and then also
i mean i i think like allowing yourself
to i guess i'm just thinking about
change and like how
how those moments can be truly powerful
like a lot of you know
lsd or mushrooms like a lot of times you
could have those realizations that
last like they'll they'll you take them
into your sober waking life
and it changes kind of who you are and
it's like a it's it's like a little gift
and i think it's beautiful that you said
um uh
like your perspective changing and
growing about moving away from your
hometown whereas you're like oh was i
running from something or
i felt that i was running from from from
kind of my old life or trying to deny it
or whatever but
i think that is the beauty of life and
especially our modern day lives is
is you notice that it's kind of in
stages you know i look back at my old
self and and i'm like
oh like i'm not like that at all anymore
but instead of feeling shame for it i'm
like oh i had to be that way so now i
could be like this
you know i had to learn those lessons so
you kind of
uh stop trying to like control so much
and just kind of let
okay what that's what i needed back then
at that age but
now that i'm this this age now that i'm
29 now that i'm 30 whatever
what do i need now what's right for me
going forward
um you know it's like we do get too
caught up with trying to
trying to fulfill something that's
already left in a sense right
yeah absolutely and that's that feeling
of guilt i realized like
okay so if i'm constantly in the state
of
feeling like well you know i'm happy
here
and i'm progressing here and i'm doing
better here but
you know i should move home because
that's you know that's my family like
you know i'm i should be close to them
it's like well
if i'm feeling guilt in the present
moment
about that then i'm not really moving
forward
in the place that i'm actually i'm
staying here because i'm like i have
this guilt because i'm staying here
because i'm doing well
so it's like just accept what it is and
as soon as you let go of that
then you're able to actually reduce the
guilt because you'll be moving forward
and doing things that are better in your
life that you you don't have to
feel bad because you're like look like
again it's if i'm taking care of me
that's the
you know most important thing for my
parents to feel like okay like
we don't have to worry about crystal
she's happy she has a support
system you know she's moving forward in
her career like we don't have to worry
about her
so that kind of helps to take care of
that guilt
that was hanging over my head the whole
time you know so you actually as soon as
you do that you can really do the things
that you need to do
in order to make yourself
feel good because that's ultimately what
we want for you know when you think
about like caring for someone else too
it's like you want them to be happy
but and i feel like in relationships too
that honoring yourself is so important
because so often like
when you look at arguments when i
reflect back to things i do and how i
acted i'm like
okay was that actually you know the way
that
did that happen because it happened and
you know things were off or did that
happen because
you weren't taking care of you and so
you let things kind of spiral and get to
a point where it's like
it's not your fault that i'm feeling
like this it's actually it's my fault
so that has actually alleviated a lot of
issues
to you know you know any sort of
compromises or things that happen um
because you get to like reflect like
okay like i actually wasn't taking care
of myself like i
wasn't working out and i was eating
terrible and
you know then i like felt bad about
myself my confidence was down and so
then these little things reflect like
and it's simple little things too you
know like
i guess like little tips will happen and
it's like are you mad at me and it's
like
well if i'm asking if you're mad at me
then is it something that i did or is it
you're mad at me you know so i think
it's really important to
like honor yourself and that has been
something that has like stuck with me
like
wait stop reflect is this because of
them or is it because you're not doing
something for you
yeah that that self-sovereignty is very
important
yeah i i really like that perspective
yeah because
because you know we get older and we see
young people we'll see a little kid
you know imagine a six-year-old girl
throwing a fit and her mom's like ah
she's super hungry she needs a nap
she doesn't know because she's still
young and her brain is still forming and
and so so she she leans on her mother
her mom
to like oh i'm grumpy and i need to eat
okay thanks mom
like you're gonna make me sandwich or
whatever but we get older and we kind of
forget that we still kind of have these
little
these little boy little girl things
going on like we'll be
you know we're we're yelling at our
significant other we're kind of like
being a [__] to them
and then in the end you know and then
you have a
bowl of mac and cheese or something and
you're just looking at him i love this
guy
yeah he's so great you know and you just
realized the whole time you're just kind
of
hungry kind of hangry you know and it's
it really is you know
you don't got to get mean to yourself
about it but really a lot of things a
lot of our emotions a lot of our moods
get carried away based off of you know
like you said oh i haven't been working
out i haven't been
i haven't been eating correctly you know
dude if you drank alcohol
last saturday and now it's wednesday you
still might be feeling some of the
effects from that alcohol like
i mean technically scientifically you're
still you still are but
it's kind of hard a subtle body to
notice but um yeah we kind of have to
we have to police ourselves in a maybe
not police ourselves but
we just got to be aware that we're
humans with emotions and in a mill
should happen you know
well and i actually had a really good
conversation the other night too we were
just kind of talking about
like um
i don't know how to put into words we
were talking about like how
so often like our natural tendencies are
to like do things so that we're
comfortable
right like always making sure that we're
comfortable but
you know when you really look at things
like your growth and things
that happen that are beneficial to you
happen
often when you're uncomfortable like
when you're struggling like
in times of like things that don't feel
good
a lot of good can come from so it's the
importance of like
accepting that struggle or accepting
being uncomfortable
and knowing that okay like it's not
gonna feel good
but knowing that it's got a good
outcome or there's something good to
come of it so it's important to not
always try to make ourselves like
yep i want to feel happy all the time i
want to feel
good i want to feel like secure
it's those moments where you aren't
secure where you are struggling where
you are that helps you to like
okay how do i get comfortable from here
what do i need to do to make myself get
too comfortable
and as soon as you get comfortable
that's when you stop growing so you
always want to
have that little push to like okay i'm
comfortable now how do i get
uncomfortable again
so i can work towards that next stage of
all right now i'm comfortable here
and you'll brush up against stuff that
that's just saying hey it's time to grow
you got to grow from this
you know it's uh my friend brandon and i
um brandon cruz who
uh he runs wild productions he we made
uh that that video
together a couple weeks ago he's super
dope um he's really good at what he does
but so we went snowboarding a few weeks
ago and
uh our vibe together like when him and i
are hanging out dude we're just
we're seriously a couple of hippies like
him and i just we riff so well together
that our heads are just way up in the
clouds
anytime we're hanging um he just brings
me up super high
but uh we we get up there and we kind of
got got a little bit of a late start
no complaints there we were like yeah no
big deal whatever big no it's fine we'll
just eat breakfast and get on the road
already started off to a good start we
get there and the parking lot's full
and so we had to park pretty far away so
we're like ah well looks like we're
gonna have to walk a little bit or we're
gonna have to park
somewhere unideally and uh catch a
shuttle
we get our gear on and we're like
talking to people and we realize that
there's no shuttle
and it's about like a mile and a half
two miles um
up to the to the lifts and it wasn't
even like we didn't even skip a beat it
was just we started
we just started walking and uh we were
talking about it
you know we could have complained we
could have like walked up there like
this sucks dude like let's put our thumb
out try to get a ride or
whatever and we did get a little bit of
rat at the very end but um
but what i'm getting at is we started
saying uh
this thing that i kind of say to myself
putting it into words out loud was
this is not my preference and you know
you it's crazy how powerful that is
because we could be catastrophic about
like oh my gosh this thing is happening
like
this is the worst but the truth is if
if you can really just say this isn't my
preference but i still am the one to
deal with it
i'm still i'm still the only person to
have to go through this
um you know you can't just you can't put
that over everything like someone who's
experienced
great levels of pain you can't be like
well you didn't get your preference bro
but you know there is there's a lot of
just realizing you know when you're
being overly dramatic when you're being
overly catastrophic or
overly um you know moody or whatever it
is
you just got to realize oh i'm just not
getting my preference and it's up to me
how i respond to this thing it has
nothing to do there's no innate
it's uh life is life is not happening to
you life is happening for you you know
it's your just it's your response
to the things that are going on in the
exterior world
yeah that's one thing that we talk about
often like living in a city like there's
times where you deal with traffic
and like you can sit in that trap and be
like what the [__] like why isn't it
moving like and get
angry but like ultimately it's not going
to change the outcome
so why spend that time just working
yourself up when it's like
okay i've learned this like i should
leave an extra 30 minutes earlier
looking this time like you know let's
maybe not plan to leave at this time and
you know you re-evaluate things but
there's no sense in getting super super
worked up over
something that's you know taking
it's up to you of how you respond to
that um
emotions are tough with that is always
challenging yourself to
all right check my emotions i'm feeling
this and like it could go to the extreme
here
how can i bring it back in yes
absolutely you
you've got to learn to self-regulate
especially in this modern fast-paced
technological world there's a lot going
on there's a lot of information coming
in a lot of information going out we've
got a
we've got to self-regulate we've got to
honor ourselves we've got to be polite
to ourselves you know and just
oh i was caught up in that oh thing i
was just kind of angry hey
sorry buddy like sorry to do that i'm
working on this whatever
you know most of the time if this has to
do with some sort of interaction or
argument with another person
or you're moody to another person
majority of the time you just tell them
you know half hour later hey sorry about
that man just just kind of got hungry a
little little cranky didn't mean to yell
at you or whatever it is
and most times they're like oh wow
thanks so much no big deal that's cool i
get angry too
so like a revolver it's a snowball
effect right like you can either
have it snowball and have it be you know
this huge terrible thing
or you can have it snowball and like use
that to help you
build something yes absolutely um
so i so i wanted to switch switch over
to you know i
always think of of hair stylists are the
ultimate
counselors do you do you ever like feel
like that and not in like a
oh man everybody just comes in here and
gets everything but right now
i feel like you're you it seems to me
like you would likely probably have to
be
focusing a lot on your on your like
emotional physical health right now so
you can show up as strong because
people are going through it right now
man everybody's going through it and
when they sit in your chair like
you might be one of the first people
that like has really listened to them
in a while and i'm sure naturally you
know the beauty of the
the you know client customer
relationship that you guys can have
you know i'm sure you guys probably do
get like like pretty open with each
other or you know the client gets open
with you
so what what have you noticed you know
in the
i guess over like over the course of all
your years of of doing this and doing
hair and
working with clients but especially with
covid like what's been coming up a lot
and what have you found yourself you
know giving advice for or saying a lot
this year's been very interesting
because
at the beginning like march 15th was a
day that we close and we go from
like i said super fast pace everyone's
going to do it
um and then it was like you didn't go
back to work until
june 23rd so during those six months and
a lot of people are working from home
during that time you know so they're
you know things have changed and their
day-to-day is
much different but they're still
preoccupying their brain so beginning of
covet for me was like
okay like how do i find something to
make myself feel
you know like i'm being productive so
um working out was a huge thing for me i
would like meet up with my friends my
great guys meet me on zoom and i would
take them through a workout and that was
like
what kept my sanity and then
fast forward to june and people are you
know they're anxious to get their hair
done you have a whole mix of people some
people are here and some people are down
here some people haven't left their
house or talked to anyone or gone
anywhere and some people are like i
can't [__] wait for the [__] to end
so it's been interesting that each
person is very different
but what i've found with being back and
kind of the ups and downs because then
summer kind of hit
and like when i first went back people
were kind of relaxed because
weather's nice they're outside they're
able to kind of like let go the covet
stuff a little bit at least where it's
not like
thinking or like your every thought and
then move forward into like the past few
months
and it almost feels like we've
regressed in that sense where people are
kind of you know they get scared again
we have a second wave of like
people getting very sick and um you know
people are now been working from home
but the interesting thing is like a lot
of people haven't had any like human
like touch like actual connection so
that's been something that i feel very
privileged in a sense to be able to
constantly have that human connection
and you know sometimes people are very
weary and you can feel that you know
like hesitancy and it's been
you know talking to them about you know
what's changed in their life like how is
it adapting to working at home
and you know some people are like this
is actually really nice like
i get so much more work done i get to
have my morning breakfast and work out
like i'm on my own schedule
and some people are like i am so sick
like if i have to sit in my
house you know having breakfast lunch
and dinner and then i get off work and
i'm still in that same environment it's
hard to separate the
work and life balance so all over the
place with that but um
you know i was anxious to come on here
and talk and i'm like why would i mean
just to talk like this is what i do for
a living i literally like
that's what i do and it's so so nice i
feel like i learned so much from my
clients and
i in turn you know hope that they feel
the same
um but it's really really it's rewarding
you know you get to when people have a
bad day
you get to come and you're like all
right we're not going to talk today
you're just going to sit you're going to
enjoy this i'm going to give you a nice
head massage and then you know you're
going to feel elevated by the end
they're talking they're happy they're
smiling
um so that's that's really really nice
um
and two it's like i get to like hear
about all these good books to read and
good movies to watch and like that's and
the whole topic of uh
what are you watching i'm like why
haven't you watched like so that's the
definite thing but it's it's nice too
and i always try to make a
conscious effort to check and like how
are you doing like how is
you know how's the pandemic affecting
you like mentally
and physically and so it's been really
really nice to be able to be going into
work
and talking to people and you know being
that outlet for
them to let loose whatever they're
feeling
yeah i'm sure crystal you provide a lot
of people with with
immense value by just you know of course
elevating them like making them look
good which gives us more confidence
you know obviously just human touch
getting that oxytocin the chemical
release when we touch each other like
um that trust of you know because
standing in line six feet apart someone
gets three feet and you're like what are
you doing dude
we're doing the six feet thing don't you
know and so really breaking those
barriers i'm sure you probably noticed
you know just the
the tension in people's neck and
shoulders and back of their head even
just
like from when they first sit down
versus when they get up
and that's that's super wonderful you
know i
i think um comedians for example they
bring
you know they're they're telling a story
but it's not so much about like the
actual words they're using it's kind of
about the feeling like they want to make
people laugh
they want to make people feel joy and
however they can do that it's you know
it's like
everybody has their own specific you
know authentic ways of doing that
um but yeah in in in hairstylist you
know you get to make people feel
feel joy in in confidence and i think
it's really important
um especially right now because like i
said we're
we're separated we're we're not touching
each other we're not i uh
yesterday i went to piano lessons
yesterday and uh
i had met her uh boyfriend or husband
for the first time
and without thinking about it just
because i was like in there in their
home she just does piano lessons out of
her house
i was like oh you know hey man nice nice
to meet you i shook his hand and then
right afterwards i was like
crap like i feel bad because i hope i
wasn't just too intense for him and so
he's like oh crap i'm gonna
you know because you there's this weird
unspoken
i want to respect your boundaries
because i understand if you're totally
terrified still because you know i've
been there
with the covet stuff so it's still this
interesting thing so it's very cool that
you can really break down a lot of those
barriers by just
doing what you do and showing up and
doing it well and just being there for
them holding that space
it is really nice um and it is like it's
always
it's tough because there's this like
level of like all right i
and my clients are coming in like can i
hug you and like i'm like
at this point where you know we're
wearing masks we're you know protective
over there i'm like yes like if you want
to hug i will give you a hug
um but with that too like there's
there's so much more people like you can
tell like
they'll first come in and they may feel
some way and then by the end they feel
another for
instance the other day i had a client
and i like kovit
um not that like copper but i'm thankful
for covid
slowing us down in the sense of like i
really do like
i take more time and just like thinking
about like what people are going through
and i like
reach out to people so it's not so much
about like oh did i make them feel
pretty it's like
you want to connect with people you want
to check in and see how they're doing
and
uh this woman hadn't seen her for a
while and she crossed my mind so i was
like i'm just gonna shoot her attacks
and she's like crystal you must have esp
or
or something because she's like i was
just thinking about usually
i'm actually gonna call this afternoon
to make an appointment so i've been
having like a really tough couple of
months
and i'm just really thankful you reached
out so
i felt super good about that she came in
the other day
and um i never with covered
um restrictions i tried to have too many
people in at once but it was just me and
one other stylist so
just finishing up with my client and her
color was processing
and so i'm finished having to come over
and she's like hey she's like i'm sorry
she's like i have to be out by this time
and i'm like oh my god i'm so sorry like
i felt bad that like i
i felt i didn't like ask her when you
know when she had to be out and it's
never usually a thing
um and you know we talked and like had a
good start to our thing but at the end
like i was like all right well let me
just trim you like i'll get you blow
dried so you can
leave out and like she left and i was
just like i felt so unsatisfied because
she had earlier reached out
you know saying she's going through a
lot and i felt like i couldn't give that
last final like
you know i was rushing through that end
i didn't get to take my time and i
wanted to make her feel good
right so a couple days go by and
just last night i was like all right i'm
gonna send her text because we talked
about a book
that i had read and i was like she's
like some
like historical fiction and i read this
awesome book about world war ii
and it's like a romance novel so just
sent her a picture but i was like hey
i just want you know i'm thinking about
you like um i'm so bummed that i didn't
get to
take the time to you know give you a
good full service and she's like
i was actually just gonna text you she's
like i'm so sorry she's like
i shouldn't have left like that she's
like and you know she's like i'm just
going through so much and like my
emotions are all over
so it was just nice to like have this
full circle thing of
you know checking in and wanting to make
her feel good and then i feel like i let
myself down because i was like i'm gonna
make her i'm gonna change her day around
and then i didn't do that and then i'm
like [__] so
oh it's been all good though like so if
people are feeling a lot right now
um but it's nice to be able to take that
step and kind of push the boundaries on
things too
yeah yeah we we really put we put a lot
of pressure on ourselves right now don't
we you know it's like
i mean and such a it's such a beautiful
thing though that you really approach
approach your job you know in in as many
aspects as you can as
you know i get to improve this person or
prove this person's day i get to like
talk to them i know they're going
through some stuff we can chat about it
and it's going to help them out or
whatever and you want to show up as that
as that person and it's also cool just
like we were saying
you know sometimes we get a little moody
or sometimes we get a little caught up
or sometimes we get you know
there's a lot going on right now it's
immense it's crazy and so the fact that
you guys are able to
after a couple days text each other or
contact and say like
hey it's all good you know it's all um
you know like i was thinking about you
you know i i think that's
that's that's pretty powerful it's
something to remember you know with
with all the news media and social media
there's very much this narrative that we
all know of you know us versus them or
the other guys or the bad guys or they
or them or whatever
and i think we've got to remember that
we're all part of this we're all like we
all have
almost almost a responsibility just as
like citizens to each other
of remembering like hey we're all going
through this right now we're all going
through
some level of this like you know like
you said some people are doing really
well from this some people
needed this time in in interiorly and to
take the time with themselves and
self-assess and readjust and maybe
wonder why they're doing their business
or reassess their business whatever it
is
but a lot of people you know especially
extroverted people i
i feel like who are used to being around
all day or being around other people
where
we're all just going through it so as
long as we can we can always cut through
the [__] of what everybody says we
should be caring about and just
you know you know put your hand on their
forearm and say hey
are you good because i got you if not
like if you need to talk let's go talk
you know and that's
and with that when you're reaching out
making sure that you're coming from a
place that
you can that you can
i guess make sure that you take the time
for yourself and that you can see like
when you're
feeling off that you don't extend you
know can't pour from an empty glass i
always say like
if you're struggling don't be afraid to
you know take the steps to take care of
that because it's important because
otherwise you try to
fix the way you're feeling by all right
let me let me do this for them
let me do this for let me make her feel
better if you're not doing that for
yourself
then you really can't give to others
because you'll just deplete yourself and
that's when you
you know get to the tough point of like
okay like how do i move forward from
here
yes yeah i mean that's that's very true
taking care of yourself is the best way
to take care of other people
you know you've got it you got to take
care of this vessel before you can
you can help other people take care of
theirs that's for sure
um hey uh do you remember when we went
uh it was it's been i don't remember how
many years it's been quite a few years
now
but i went over after one of one of my
shows i think i was working
in atlanta
oh yeah yeah yeah i was working atlantic
city and came back over
and then dude we just had such a good
time i mean i totally agree with what uh
mike and lana were saying about your
friends like literally just such
wonderful people
like all will's friends just so
welcoming i felt like i had like a
like such a vibe with everybody everyone
was so accepting all your friends
it was so great everybody was so
wonderful but uh we went to
so one cool place we went to was uh like
uh a thrift store where we found a
sweatshirt kelso high which is wild
and then also uh remember the the
warehouse
like okay you know it's so crazy the
warehouse that you walked in and there's
like a secret room there's that swing
and the bar
and it's dark there's literally a dude
who's like
right this way and he's like moving
plywood over it's like
it was so crazy i have like i'm like
trying to figure out i have to like send
attacks and go yo really where was that
because that was the most like
i felt around like a little magical we
went in another dimension
yeah okay okay describe this uh we'll
mention the kelsey sweatshirt thing but
describe this okay so we're out we're
having drinks you know we went to a
couple different places we had a really
super fun night honestly it was a great
night
so bars open it are closed at two so i
remember it was like getting close to
two o'clock and um i have a lot of
friends in nightlife and they're like oh
we can go to this spot
and so i feel like it was on um
columbus boulevard which is down like
south philly there's a bunch of like
larger
big buildings um it's like a warehouse
and there's a front entrance i think it
might have been um it's like a strip
club now in the front park but there's
this back door entrance
and so we went up that you like walk up
the stairway and then it was like an
empty hallway
and there was like you know some windows
at the end but
the one door you open and then you're in
like uh
it was probably like 800 square feet um
dark there was a bar it was like i feel
like it was like very like black and red
and
yeah yeah very dimly lit and then
that little stage was like a big wooden
swing
yes and um yeah i mean very cool people
very very chill but we went there for a
couple hours and continued our
our night on i have to double check and
see where that is though because that's
like one of the mysteries of
my dude that place was so inspiring to
me i remember
i feel like my my last house in the
basement like my um
like little studio i had there i was
very inspired by that
that night that we had like because i
remember they had this section of the
wall where people had written kind of
like profound
you know like like hippie philosophical
thoughts or like
kind of shower thoughts yeah and then
there and there's
actual like beautiful art too and it was
just this there's like always something
to look at and you're
you're like reading profound things as
you're and it had this very
it also had this very like vip
experience to it
in a weird like life yeah it was uh
yeah and so uh that that experience was
just
was just wild like how our night just
just trickled there it was this little
hole in the wall for like a certain
amount of people at a certain time in
the night
and man that was cool [__] that was like
the best way to i don't know if that was
my first time in philly but it was
second time maybe yeah i think it was
your second actually
um because i was at my new apartment
with melissa
but that's the thing that i love about
philly is like like i say
i came out here and you know i had
softball so it was nice i had my group
of people but i always say like if
you're coming here like
no matter what you're into or um
what your beliefs are or what kind of
music you like
but whoever you want to be there is
something here for you
and like food there's so much good food
there's so it's just so diverse
and there's so much opportunity for you
to truly be yourself that's why i will
forever
appreciate philly for allowing me to
become me here there was no like cookie
cutter way you have to do it like this
it's like come as you are yes i agree
with the good food shout out stuffed
buns for sure
we went to a couple other good a couple
really good places too but
uh we talked about this actually like i
called you not long after
after my not really that recent anymore
but after my last
my breakup i called you and that was a
lot of what our conversation was is
is kind of i was like i you know i kind
of want to like get out of here i kind
of want to like just go experience the
world i want
to want to check it out i want to see
what's up and and that was a lot of
a lot of our conversation is kind of
like um
how how freeing it can be to you know
not just leave your hometown but
but to go to a place that is so
accepting of
like you just being the fullest extent
of your being
and that's i totally get that vibe from
philly i felt
felt very comfortable there everybody
was very welcoming
i didn't feel um there's no like tension
i had i just felt like i could just try
to you know
be myself whatever that means yeah i
think the challenging thing
in any situation and you know as you
we we're supposed to change we're
supposed to grow and i think the hardest
thing is
you know we do that at different rates
so it's tough when you're around people
who are
always there and they're like wait
you're you don't think like that or you
don't
you don't do that like i know you it's
hard to break yeah it's hard to break
down
yourself when you're constantly being
challenged by the people around you
so that's the one thing the people that
i have here i'm so thankful for them
like
a lot of my connections started because
of the girls i played softball with and
like i said i just saw the one um did
her hair yesterday
and she went from you know being
she was in communications just doing
whatever and now she's going to school
for nursing i had a friend rachel
um she went to school and now has a food
truck like
we all have like gone to school done our
thing and then we're like oh pivot we're
gonna do this
i became a hair stylist like so we're
always and we're always there to support
each other like
and that's i think the important thing
is being around people who when you do
change it's not like
why are you changing it's like all right
what can we do to help like
you know we're behind you like you know
there's always going to be times again
like getting uncomfortable time to
struggle times of
you know doubt and in those times it's
about being like
open to accepting that like okay this is
part of it this should be happening like
that it's okay that you feel that way
it's okay that you're questioning this
like i understand why you're thinking
that way
however you know you can do this or that
and so
it's important to be able to accept
someone else changing
you know and understanding what you know
going through
that can be like and just to just
support so
yeah what people wh what came up for me
is the
uh i forget who exactly has said it this
way but um
courage is action in the face of fear
not the absence of fear
and i think that sometimes certain
people
like just off of their reactions to like
what you tell them or what you're doing
with your life like
um how incredibly encouraging it can be
to still take action in the face
of fear when just one person is like all
right bro it's like yeah maybe you
should give that a shot
yeah oh yeah you you were yeah i think
you'd be good at that cool
you know and that could be like that
could seriously spark an entirely
different life path
for someone by just having someone
that's encouraging or not
um you know i i find
i find you know let's say family for
example family can sometimes be
the first people to say you know
like oh are you sure you want to do that
hon you know are you sure you want to be
because they care about you they don't
want you to they don't want to see you
fail they don't want to see you you know
run out of money they don't want to see
whatever um because you know they love
you how you are
and they're they're like will you stay
the same and that'll be fine and you're
great how you are why would you want to
change
but if there's something internally
where you're wanting to
to grow to change to explore new sides
of yourself to step into a new stage of
your life
um that one person who who's just saying
hey like i i would accept you if you did
that yeah i think it'd be cool if you
tried to do that
that that can be very very encouraging
absolutely
and i think too it's like you know with
the comfort thing it's like okay
i feel like i can level myself up if i
do this
however it's going to set me back
financially or it's going to take a few
years for me to get there it's like some
people are scared to get out of their
comfort zone and take that risk
of you know seeing what they're capable
of and so i think it's important to keep
people around you that keep you grounded
you know they're not like all right quit
your job and go you're going to write a
book you know but
also if you eventually want to write a
book it's you know
okay what can we do to help you push a
boundaries and allow yourself to be able
to
you know take those chances right
yeah instead of you know where whereas
some relationships
you'll be around that are just like
you're going to write a book
what do you have to write about you know
or the the
just kind of like like back back to
where you were saying you know
people accidentally like they think they
know everything about you you know it's
just like
when you go to your family family
thanksgiving
sometimes your uncle sees you as the 16
year old version of yourself and not
like
the grown ass 30 year old adult you know
so oh yeah
yeah being being around like-minded
people and
you know i think more and more people
are doing that i think uh you know as
as maybe it's just something that
happens with age two as you kind of
grow out of your own like young [__]
even or your own
your young um non-believing in yourself
you start a car you kind of start to
notice that you enjoy being around
people who
are encouraging for your future self not
just the person who they wish you would
stay yeah absolutely i think that's one
thing
like i say too with like family you know
it's tough
because your family is your family and
like
that's you know we grow up and of course
like we're influenced by them
and i think the important thing is like
you know i have a lot of friends who
have
you know found out that
you know things that they've been doing
or the direction that they're going
isn't for them or
you know their sexual orientation
orientation is different than what
they've exposed and
so i think it's hard um to
press the boundaries and to sometimes
your family who you
are the closest with are the hardest
ones to be able to open up to
who you really are so it's important to
be able to
look at things and you know find a
balance and like
just because you may do something that
they may not see in that moment as
what's right if you know it's right for
you it's important to be able to take
those steps
and to you know keep pushing one foot in
front of the other and maybe
right away they won't see that it's
right but
if you're doing what's right for you
then you will never be
let down you know so and i think a lot
of people have
gone to that point where you know it's
either scary or they're unsure
and you know maybe there are some
wavering things um
that are tough like for me personally
like moving out here it was like okay
and then when are you coming home when
are you coming home what are you coming
home
and then to finally be like okay you
know like i
i'm really happy here i have a good
support system like and then
with that they're like we're so proud of
you like we don't worry about you
it's nice that you have these people i'm
never like concerned about
if you're okay we know you're okay so
you know those things that were really
tough and that i was
super you know scared to like finally be
like
i don't i don't know when i'm coming
home that was like when
they were like you know you're all right
you know so
just pushing past those boundaries and
then if people don't support you
then you know it's their loss and at
some point
they'll either see that oh you know they
made the mistake
um or they'll see things your way and
that's you know that can come but
it's just important to live
authentically to yourself because that's
at the end of the day at our
our last i guess decision making and
things like that
if you do things that feel good for you
right
yeah you've got to trust that that inner
guidance that inner intuition that
you know your soul your essence your
whatever you want to call it whatever
feels right to you i mean
we all have some sort of connection to
regardless of how you get there whatever
wordings like some an internal being
of like ah this doesn't feel right you
know this is where your gut feeling is
it's where you're
like you're your ultimate decision
making when it's not based off of just
trying to impress other people or
do what other people want for you there
there is we all have this thing
where this just feels right for me so i
need to do it and
yeah i think it's very we should
definitely encourage people to lean into
that and then also
encourage um try to notice when we're
maybe accidentally being a little
like holding on a little too tight maybe
as family members or something or
or even friends and just allowing people
to
to follow their intuition i think is is
very important
um hey i was thinking so you've you
i think you you're probably pretty young
when you started softball
you've been into sports for a long time
so what was your transition
like after sports like what what was
that about because
you and you can give like a little bit
of about for people who don't know like
any of your
um accolades when it comes to to sports
and then kind of what was your
transition out of that
yeah so um it's interesting i traveled
all my weekends in high school i was
playing travel softball and
knew i wanted to get a scholarship and
no idea what i wanted to go to school
for but
i knew i wanted to play softball um
so i end up getting a couple different
offers
a lot of east coast schools i got
recruited late in my
senior year and when i was really i was
two or three my dad worked for boeing so
we were actually we lived in
philadelphia for
like a year two years maybe um
[Music]
that's why i viewed some schools in like
south carolina north carolina uh new
york and philly
and just really messed with the people
when i came on my official visit
and also i was like all right like i
lived here when i was younger like it
felt like it was
a part of me somehow so um
came here freshman year i had a great
year
um sports wise academically wise i
really struggled i
thought i wanted to do physical therapy
and then i found out with traveling and
playing sports
very very difficult um just high demand
of
a lot of like studying a lot of labs and
stuff so
that my sophomore year um it's really
interesting my
coach was like all right look i want you
to
get tested and um he's like i think you
have a d like i want you to get on
medication so
that was a whole whirlwind of thing that
year i look back at the amount of
adderall that they put me on and i'm
like it's literally insane i was on like
80 milligrams a day
i would take we'd wake up at 5 00 a.m
for weights
and then you would go to classes
and then um we had to take a bus out to
ambler which was like a 35 minute ride
so after class is 2 30 you catch the bus
you go practice you get home
around like eight o'clock at night and
then you study and then you go to bed
you wake up and do it again
traveling on weekends for games and
stuff like that um
but when i started the medication
they would have me take 220 milligrams
in the morning
and then two in the afternoon and i was
just like a
[__] machine yeah and
you know school i would switch to
communications because they're like it's
the easiest thing to
um do if you're unsure about what you
want to do
with that i was school-wise and so
i'm best like i was in the best shape of
my life but also just selling healthy um
you know naturally we had the partying
and stuff like that but um
just like i was running on
amphetamines and i'd go to the gym in
the morning and work out
uh for like our actual weeks and then by
the time i was getting done i saw so
much energy i would go and run
you know three miles on the treadmill
before i went in and then
studying and you're waking up and doing
it all over and then i got injured
um my freshman year i had re-tore my
knee that was a quick fix but that was
at the end of the season
sophomore year pretty early on i um
had hurt my shoulder when i went in for
my
mri they were like yeah like you tore
your um
partially toward your rotator cuff but
you're young like you should be able to
rehab
and um be able to play so spent all this
time like
rehabbing and i remember i was getting
ready for uh to get clearance to play
felt good and i threw one last ball at
the end and
um i like just a shooting pain and i
like played it up i'm like
i'm fine i'm good i'm good like yep
ready to go and i get to the bus i
remember calling my dad just sobbing i'm
like i'm not okay like i'm so hurt
like and he's like you know like tell
them that you're
you're not feeling right and it's been
like at this point
probably three months of me rehabbing
and i'm like in my head they're telling
me that i should be fine so i'm like am
i hypochondriac like is there something
wrong with me
and um so i finally totally went into
the office i'm like
i i can't fake this like i really i'm in
a lot of pain
so i went in and i did a contrast like a
die contrast
mri and we're so sorry you actually have
a fully torn label
and a partially torn rotator cuff and we
have to do surgery
and so when i was going in for a
consultation about that they're like you
have like a 70
recovery rate and i'm going from being
you know a full ride
starting player to we don't know it
depends on your recovery
what will come after this you know and
at that time too i had
um my mom was home and i had an older
brother who's
um had years of issues with addiction
and uh i just felt like my mom really
needed me then so
i was there like i said i went there to
play softball and school was kind of
like all right like i'm doing this
because that's the route that you're
supposed to take
without any like i guess real idea of
knowing what i wanted for myself so when
i had that opportunity to
reflect and look at things i was like
all right i'm gonna go be i'm gonna go
help my mom like i'm gonna go
be there for her be close for my family
so moved home right away
um dealt with my injury and
that was a big part of it too is going
from like taking all that adderall and
then coming home to a normal
day where i'm not waking up at five a.m
and i'm not doing stuff
and i'm like yeah i'm still taking this
i felt like a crazy person
so it was a long time of adjusting to
just normal life
um and i had moved in at home first and
then like
my mom and i didn't it didn't work with
us um
being home so i moved out moved up to
bellingham that's why i was in
bellingham for
about six months and then i was getting
to the point where i'm like okay
like what's next for me i thought i was
gonna go to school right away
again still hadn't figured out what i
wanted to do
and um with the shoulder being
such a like i couldn't reach my back
seat for the longest time
and so i didn't think hair never even
crossed my mind so it wasn't until
i'd been home um and again my sister and
i were gonna move in with my mom for a
little bit and she's like ah
like this situation came up and we ended
up getting a lease
for um in kelso for a year
and after that was like okay well look
let's figure out like what comes next
for you you know long is kind of in the
same situation where she had gotten her
associates and she was going to go to a
four year
and we were both like what do we want to
do and i still had a bunch of
connections from
the girls that i played with they're
like come out here move back like we
want you back out here
and so i was just looking for myself at
that point so
i loaded up the car load up the dogs
lana came with me
and it was like a good let's see that
was 2013.
so like good three years kind of just
stumbling around i worked i
got a good job with um some friends
working as a staff and coordinator just
because of connections
and it wasn't until i was doing that for
a year
i had to take out my piercings and hide
my tattoos and remember i
shaved the side of my head they're like
um can you part your hair the other way
and i finally one day i was like
[__] it like i don't want to be someone
i'm not every day so
i looked into um hair school i thought i
wanted to go for makeup at first
and then um got there and totally fell
in love with the hair thing and looking
back i'm like
for all the dances for all like i used
to be
getting ready in college and my friend
speak can you do my makeup and do my
hair and i felt like guys like i'm not
getting anyone ready because i'm always
getting you ready and then you're like
come on crystal we gotta leave so
it's always been a passion but it was
really nice it took a good
three years to find like right something
that i
was good at a passion something that
made me feel
as good as you know playing softball did
so
definitely a whirlwind of trial and
error
and it just kind of stumbled into it
and then once i found out that that was
something that i could do and feel good
and
got excited about then it was just hit
the ground running
so yeah yeah i think stumble through is
the perfect word for it because you know
you you think you're going to have this
certain trajectory
or you don't even think about it and
you're just doing you're just like
waking up as the machine every day just
working because you're accomplishing
this goal that you set out to do like
way back when you were younger when you
started in sports or whatever
um and then you and then you get like
you said you you couldn't even
reach back into your back seat let alone
think about
like styling someone's hair and here you
are now so it's it's crazy how how life
works like that isn't it you know we
we don't really know how
how we're gonna get there you just kind
of have to i guess trust or
or have a little faith that it's going
to be okay or that
you know if you just kind of keep going
you keep chugging along you keep like
trying to listen to the
to the friends to the voices to the
intuitions whatever
um and you'll kind of find yourself in a
seat
at some point absolutely do you
it's a lot of like not beating yourself
up like you know there's times where
like i said like you have a full right
scholarship you're supposed to go to
school
that's what you're supposed to do so i
spent a lot of time like
did i [__] up like did i ruin everything
because i didn't push through because i
let my injury just kind of control
because i let you know my worry of my
home life
you know control things and it's that
exact thing that
i'm like i would not be where i am today
had i not made those decisions had i not
chosen to do things the way that i did
so it's you know
finding taking your mistakes
or taking your decisions and reflecting
and finding out
you know well what was that for what was
the purpose of that and then
you know using those two there are
certain things that really are eating
you alive and decisions that you
don't like that you can't live with like
okay well how do i make sure that
doesn't happen again
so i think that's the important part but
ultimately again the struggle
and the uncomfortability
is all all worth something it all gets
you somewhere so
it's not to put down feeling doubt
or uncertainty and things like that but
to find okay well how do i make myself
feel more certain to feel less doubtful
yeah you know and i i think just by you
sharing sharing your story of like you
know kind of like
i ended up in a place that that feels
pretty right i think that's
you know that in itself is helpful to
people because you know a lot of people
are going through it right now and a lot
of people are
you know maybe they're they're in that
few year period of like man what do i
want to freaking do
like what's what's going on what should
i do with my life or what
what would fulfill me and i think just
knowing that
you don't always get the answers super
quick you don't always even get the
answer so i i guess like
you just kind of keep stumbling through
and eventually you
you can get in a place where you sit
back and and realize
okay i mean this is of course i'm here
because of course everything has led me
to this spot and this is right where i'm
supposed to be so
hey i i didn't i did have a question on
um
um adderall so because
this is always a touchy subject because
i'm i always you know try to give my
recommendations or my advice of what
i've experienced but i'm also like i'm
not a [__] doctor
like be careful you know whatever but um
i've talked about me before
i was there was a while where i was on
20 milligrams i would take two tens a
day and then i lowered it back down
and that was that was just too much um
and i lowered it down to
i was down to i think i went to 15 for a
while then to 10
and it was mainly 10 and then i decided
i wanted to to get off of it i wanted to
like try to
you know work on things like meditation
and in other ways of of controlling my
attention span my focus
um my uh even kind of
sometimes like combating a weird your
tension span doesn't
keep up and so you get suddenly
immensely tired like brick wall
and adderall helped with that which is
you know the amphetamines in it but
so so i trickled down and then i i've
been off
for years now but i'm always kind of
like trying to flirt with
how can i recommend you know if anybody
else wants to get off of it without
saying like hey quit your medication
or whatever so do you have any things
like like when you were lessening your
dosage and stuff did you have anything
that that seemed to help
ah it's so tough i mean when i first was
doing it it was
just the dis or the like okay like i'm
not
crazy this is making me feel this way um
so i remember just cutting everything in
half like i simply i was like okay i'll
take one in the morning and take one in
the afternoon and i found that i'm like
i still
feel the effects of it cutting it in
half you know
um and i feel like for a while like you
just
it's really hard when you're coming off
because you feel like
tired you feel unmotivated you feel
like unproductive compared to when you
are on it
um i think it's like the same thing with
trying to quit any drug like just know
that it's so rewarding to cut yourself
off and that you're capable of
living life without it and like now like
there are times where i'm like oh i want
to clean the house like i'm going to get
an adderall for my friend i'm going to
take a half and i'm going to
you know do everything i think about
like when i was on it like that half an
hour was just for me to
or that adderall then was just for me to
get through my day so
it's interesting to see how much that it
really does affect you
and how much it really doesn't affect
you it's like with anything you build up
an immunity to it and like
you know it's like with any drugs that
one
dose will the first time you take it
you're like whoa i feel like i can fly
and then
that one dose becomes okay i need a
little bit more actually and they need a
little bit more so it's going to be this
constant like
revolving door of need a little bit more
need a little bit more so
i just really think it is like it's
tough and it's it's hard for like the
first
couple months honestly adjusting to not
having it because it's hard to like
get out of bed and get moving and then
you second guess like oh
i would have taken it i would have done
so much more but like honestly would you
have
probably not like there's so much when i
compared to like what i actually got
done
with it versus what i could accomplish
without it it's kind of
the same yeah like maybe you didn't feel
as
up and intense yeah maybe i wasn't like
up but
yeah we're always trying to to get to
the most
optimal comfort or you know this is that
same place in us that wants that
that high in a sense too um but but i
think
you know we have our society
it seems like so many people you know
because the internet is so available to
us because you know
like anybody who's going through some
sort of symptoms can follow you know a
few weeks of
youtube rabbit holes and then they're
like whoa okay i didn't realize it
before but i have adhd or whoa i didn't
realize it but i'm ocd or
whatever and there's
there's some extent which is very good
because people are like oh wow jesus
that now i can find ways of helping me i
can find communities that are
of people like me and listen to how they
have um you know help help their
their similar issues but i i think a lot
of us
we we really latch our identity on to
like i am someone with adhd
if i didn't have this you wouldn't want
to be around me if i didn't have this
i would get nothing done if i didn't
have this i would never get out of bed
and
you know maybe this is really generally
genuinely the case for some people
and if that is so i i provide you with
with uh sympathy for sure but yeah i
think that
being able to talk about um you know
being able to get off of these things
like you don't you don't necessarily
have to
to live on high doses of of things that
if you've learned like oh it's just not
really working for the stage of my life
anymore like you had changed stages in
your life
and it just wasn't really working to try
to take the
the the nos before work every day you
know
yeah well i mean i think too it's like
it's the same way though i mean like
coffee but i'm like i
have coffee every single day you know
if i don't have it to me it's not like
oh i didn't get anything done i will be
like oh i have a headache because i
didn't have coffee and like i make up
these things in my head
but really it's like i probably am just
dehydrated like so there's always
something and don't get me wrong i'm the
first person to have a caffeine headache
and then i look like no i'm dehydrated
but
in that moment you're like no i have a
headache because i didn't have caffeine
so we're always constantly
you know making things that we're always
looking for
validation or for answers if you will
as to why we do or why we feel or why
but then when you reflect i think that's
the important part is to
then reflect on what you say in that
moment
is that actually the reality of what was
what i was experiencing and what was
going on
well well and i think practice is
something that's you know
for all these things like have you have
you practice
the attention because attention is a
skill you know and
for me like after i had like weaned off
adderall and even while i was still
still on it i was starting to try to
sharpen my focus try to sharpen my
attention you know i would
i'm trying to watch this you know video
this audio engineering video or whatever
and i have the urge to like oh i want to
go grab my phone or like oh i want to
like let's scroll through social media
but that's a moment where you've got to
be like oh this is where i'm training my
attention
so i'm going to say no to that feeling
and i'm going to say nope
jake you're going to focus your
attention on this video right now oh
you're floating away again cool i'm
going to find a way to keep focusing i'm
now going to get a piece of paper and
write notes about this thing so i can
focus and train my attention so you know
a lot of these
a lot of our you know um psychological
just they're not they're not bad things
they're not burdens they're not it's
just just
how we are you know just some people are
certain ways and
cool this you know you're handed in life
when you come into life you're handled
with like here's
here's what you're dealing with and you
find a way to deal with it and that's
that's your
burden burden to shoulder that's your um
you know thing to carry
and i think that a lot of times we learn
about them or like oh i have adhd and
then we're like well
now i'm not going to do anything i'm
just going to go to the doctor and he's
going to tell me what to do
and realistically there's a whole other
side of this of you know get your
medication you know if it helps you
that's great
but also be wondering okay how can i
insert
ways to focus ways to how can i try to
improve my memory
you know and there's there's literally
apps for improving your memory now
and all this stuff so there is ways to
kind of
you know launch yourself yeah yeah
totally
grow you're you're cooler on the other
side of it because you've grown now too
yeah exactly yeah well um
my friend we are getting up here in time
um i know
uh the el nine is on her way to the east
coast
so uh i i will let you go here shortly
um
i just want to say i really appreciate
you coming on crystal um i really
appreciate you doing this i know that
you communicated you were
you were nervous about it which i
totally get that so thank you for
having courage in the face of that of
that nervousness
made me comfortable so yeah good i'm
glad you were comfortable i think you
you got it you got some good advice for
people and um
it was nice to have you on here and
let's end with
i've been trying to mix up my last
questions i always like those um
[Music]
what here's what okay what has um
this last year and meaning let's say
since coven and the changes that it that
it through all the worlds
what has it taught you about yourself
um i feel like one of the biggest things
and it's like me now transitioning to
like i'm comfortable with
work and i'm happy i'm doing it
no one's going to do anything for you
like if you want something
if you want to get it no one's going to
do it for you so
and it's hard because sometimes you feel
like well i don't know how the resources
are like i don't have the
knowledge of that or like i'll never be
able to read enough to know the business
side of things or whatever it is like
you have everything within you to get
what you want so don't limit yourself
because of what you think
that you aren't capable of um
i think it's allowed me to like i said
like if you want something go get it
and i'm currently in that that phase of
realizing like okay don't
think that you're not able to do
something because
it never seemed feasible before you're
the only one standing in your way
massive massive i love that that was
like such a perfect answer okay crystal
thank you so much listeners take care of
yourselves
um check out crystal's instagram if you
want to see her
her hair and remember that when you're
looking at those pictures there's so
much more than just the picture
um and message her if you're in philly
and you need your
your weave done hit her up um
love you fake thank you so much yes love
you sis thank you have a good rest of
your day give my best to will and lana
i will i'll talk to you
[Music]
knowledge is power